CHRISTIAN APEKU

SUMMARY

Tech-savvy Web Developer with four years of experience in technical software development. Polished in wireframe and template development and functional testing.

Analytical and resourceful professional deeply familiar with the Adobe creative suite programs, Vue Js, HTML, CSS, PHP, C#, and JavaScript.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer & UI/UX Designer. 12/2022 – Current Rigelis Inc - Accra

- Designed and built a rapid test diagnosis web application using Vue Js and Firebase for database and backend analytics.
- Redesigned existing POS application user interface using Js, which is currently in production
- Designed the UI and created the front-end for two other projects using Flutter which still is in development.
- Collaborated with the customer experience and backend dev team to make various frontend changes to enhance the overall application performance and user experience.

Frontend Developer & UI/UX Designer. 09/2021 – Current Motes Systems – Accra

- Designed and built the UI and front-end for a hall management application for the University of Ghana Common wealth hall.
- Designed and built a the front-end for multiple web and mobile apps.
- Consulted clients on design changes and also did both virtual and in-person presentations during the various stages of application development. From wireframing to prototypes and final designs
- Built layouts according to customer parameters using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.



CONTACT

Location: Accra, Ghana Phone: +233501103358

Email: apekuchristian@gmail.com
Online Portfolio: capeku.github.io

SKILLS

UI/UX Design: Figma, Adobe XD, Photoshop, illustrator, Procreate.

Web and coding: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue Js, Nuxt Js, Tailwind CSS.

Version control: Git and GitHub **Word processing:** Microsoft Office, Google Docs.

Remote collaboration tools: Slack, Linear, Zoom, Google Meet.

Spreadsheets: Excel.

3d Modelling and Animation:Autodesk Maya, SketchUp, Unity
3d

Game development: Unity 3d, C#.

Co-Founder. 03/2021 – Current Yogis Itd – Koforidua

- Yogis Itd is a yogurt startup that produces high-quality, organic Greek yogurt made with locally sourced ingredients.
- As Co-founder, I am responsible for developing and executing the company's marketing strategy, overseeing product development, and managing a team of 5 employees.
- Key achievements include launching a successful influencer campaign that resulted in a 60% increase in sales, developing new yoghurt flavors that increased revenue by 20%, and securing a partnership with a retailer in Accra.

Freelance Web Developer & Social Media Manager, 09/2019 – 03-2021

- Built layouts according to customer parameters using HTML, CSS and WordPress.
- Discussed website design and function, answering questions and concerns.
- Designed and developed customized website presentation to achieve optimized goals.
- Conducted website performance tests, troubleshooting and upgrades.
- Redesigned sites to enhance navigation and improve visual appeal.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Arts, Industrial Art.

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Africa Developer Challenge.

Andela.com